Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 98 in this exercise.
We are going to implement that counting salt algorithm in Java.
So this is the package that we have created inside the project and inside the algorithms.
I will create a new Java class called Counting So Game for remembering.
You can go and download all these source codes underneath every exercise that we have solved inside
the Udemy course's resources folder under each exercise.
Now the counting sort, we will create it by using the steps that we have seen in the previous videos,
so we will follow the steps of the.
Counting sort algorithm, and we will start by making a new public void call accounting sort, this
is count counting sorting it took into the party meter.
Let me try to make this algorithm with the characters in order to change from the numbers.
OK, so from the integers first step into an equal entry at the length we get and and now the output
character and that will have to be sorted.
The final input?
OK, car output at a equal to new car.
And
now create account of a
customer count of the characters
and initialize the count rate
and.
Count they.
OK.
Don't have a as CEO.
This step number one.
Please follow me because this this algorithm is, I think it has it is very complex among all the algorithms
and that and need many attention and high attention to to understand the steps and follow the steps
so and count every equal to you.
And and I will make it through five six.
Now I will start making the follow up stuff from an equal to zero.
I mean,
less than 256.
Let me make it.
And I thus plus because the characters the table, it's limited to five six and the count at Index II
is equal to zero.
We initialize them with SEER.
OK.
We said that we need to create and add today and initialized the count array as the.
And this is this is very important step that we have learned in the previous videos and the lecture
about the counting.
So now the second step change count at the count.
Count of the Act.
And the sign.
So that count at index, I now contains
the actual position of this character in the output array.
We are working and playing with the in this index and that value.
So this array count what hat would refer to the index that of the past as a that we need to sort of
include things actual position
of this character in output.
We start by four and I equal to one I less than or equal to five five and I plus plus
we start by count at Index II plus equal to count at index minus one.
OK.
We are changing, we are making a community a out, but we are making a community as a that we are making
and adding the count of the index is equal to that count of index I should hold.
Plus the count of I minus one, this is the short cut of this mean.
Now the third step is to build that output character everyday to make it more stable where OK.
Stable, now, stable and reverse, there's not OK.
No.
Four and equal to and minus one
is greater than or equal to zero by a minus minus.
We make here that output at index.
Please pay attention for this gas.
It's very important output and counts here out at count, at index array, at index sites.
It's very complex here or there to understand the index relation equal to the because we have assigned
the index as if the value and we have learned and we have learned and make them count and counting all
the occurrences of these variables and these elements into an output as a base for that, we have made
this output that index.
This at this index.
So we are going to calculate the index this and ground this and minus one.
So the count would may be that index.
And then we have the my we have a decreased by one because we have more.
This is a very important step and we have talked it much, much in the previous videos because it's
it's needed two minus one because we hear that the traversing from trees is a very, very, very like
a very complex because we need to find this one here.
We care for the output at very creation.
OK?
Please go back to the previous videos in order to learn about these steps.
OK.
Count we decreased by count by minus one.
No copy the output at the forces that we need to display them into the output array.
So copy that output
that way to a at or if we have.
So there they are.
Five now contains.
Sorted.
Got was fought and equal to zero or less than an hour plus plus
they are at index are equal to output at index.
Oh OK.
So we are copying the output rate to array a on so that they are now contains the sorted factors.
Now let's test our very amazing code and very amazing
sorting algorithm by making is there that over codes public static void, main string args currently
and we use it sort.
Create I have create public static.
So sorting, counting, sorting, I will create and update off guard.
They are equal to.
That's dry to J.
J
Hay
and.
That
fell.
The and so we need to arrange this, so don't think so, I think we passed that at a.
OK.
This is the.
The method that we have created here.
OK, now we need to print that, hey, by making.
System that out.
Don't pretend you can make it as a method
print and
sort the character out of a
booklet here, and we make if Waterloo was entirely equal to zero by less than they the banks and I
plus plus okay.
System that holds that prevent.
They have said, and this guy
knows space.
OK.
This is that accounting sort this out of the four step that we have created, and let's run and see
our code.
There is an out of index exception here.
Let me see the output.
The output count and I.
And the airport there.
And minus one.
Index, let's check we have missed starting your step number two, it's very important storing the store
count of each character when we need it, we need to assign it and stored its count so far in by equal
to zero by less than an eye plus plus.
And we need to make the last plus count at index.
Ray.
Ah, all right.
OK.
This is how to store the count of eight.
You know, it's very simple.
No.
We need also to make.
They're on here for the kind of thing sort of thing.
And here we go, guys, we have our sorted character that they have been sorted correctly from this
to this outward.
OK.
So please guys, go back to the animations and go back to the previous videos intellectual and see how
the steps and details for the counting.
And I will see you and then next algorithms in order to learn and master.